-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
WiKi-720P时间轴校正: hkwwcl@HDC
"我们现在居住在哪"
能源即污染的状况已经持续一段时间了
There was a time when "energy" was a dirty word.
开灯与否也曾经是个艰难选择
When turning on your lights was a hard choice.
城市里的灯火管制...
Cities in brownout...
食物短缺 车辆靠吞油而行
food shortages, cars burning fuel to run.
但这些都已成往事
But that was the past.
我们现在在哪 是如何使这个世界如此多娇
Where are we now? How do we make the world so much better?
连沙漠都能迸发蓬勃生机
Make deserts bloom!
此刻  我们就是世界最大的混合能源生产商
Right now, we are the largest producer of fusion energy in the world.
太阳能投射到月岩 被其所捕获
The energy of the sun, trapped in rock,
再由月球远端的机器所开采
harvested by machine from the far side of the moon.
今日 地球所需能源总量的70％可由
Today, we deliver enough clean-burning helium-3...
我们开采的清洁能源氦-3所供给
to supply the energy needs of nearly 70% of the planet.
当时谁会想到 我们急需的能源
Who would have thought that all energy we ever needed
其实抬头可见
is right above our heads?
月能
The power of the moon...
我们明日的能源
the power of our future.
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译：alfalfa
校对：小魉
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
时间轴：小魉
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
月球
开采基地 -- 莎拉站
机组人员 -- 1人 合约时限 -- 3年
开工咯 8点32分 太平洋时间
Rock and roll! 08:32, Pacific Time.
全体采能车运转良好
All harvesters running smoothly.
数据如下
Readouts are as follows:
马修号 14.6英里
Matthew... 14.6 miles.
马克号 16.8英里
Mark... 16.8 miles.
怎么回事
I don't?
嘿 柯里? 柯里? 醒醒
Hey, Gerty? Gerty? Wake up!
早上好 山姆
Good morning, Sam!
马克号上有储满能源的了
We have got a live one on Mark!
我得出去把能源罐弄进来
I'm going to go out now and rope her in.
好的 山姆
OK, Sam.
我想来点巧克力
I want chocolate.
依我看 你够肥了
I think you're sweet enough.
别吃的好
You don't need chocolate.
远距通讯信号搜索中
Searching for long-range comms.
信号搜索失败
Signal failure on long-range comms.
山姆・贝尔 呼叫指挥中心
Sam Bell, reporting to Central...
10点14分 太平洋时间
10:14, Pacific Time.
有一能源罐已采满氦-3 准备回送
I have a full container full of helium-3, ready to roll.
当你收到这条消息时 能源罐应该已在转移途中
By the time this message reaches you, it should be in transit.
其他一切运行正常
Otherwise, everything running smoothly...
下面都还好吧
How are things down there?
你们有没有组织
You guys been having any...
派对或其他什么好玩的
good parties or anything?
哦 谢谢
Oh, thanks for the...
谢谢你的球赛转播 看上去就像实况直播一样
for the football feed! It almost felt live.
看上去像
Almost!
三年是个漫长的旅程
Three years is a long haul.
你知道 那可是相当相当相当相当的漫长
You know? It's way, way, way, way, way too long!
我在习惯性地
I'm talking to myself...
自言自语
on a regular basis!
那么
So...
该回家了 你知道我的意思对吧
Time to go home, you know what I mean?
就是那个意思 通讯结束
That's it, over and out!
开工啦 上帝保佑美国
Rock and roll, God bless America!
我能帮你完成 山姆
I can do that for you, Sam.
该死的 我说过我来做
God damn it! I said I got it!
你就不能听我的话么
Why don't you listen to me?
货物准备发射
Package ready for launch.
山姆 没事吧
Sam, is everything OK?
山姆?      干吗?
Sam?        What?
你今天看上去和平时不大一样
You don't seem like yourself today.
出问题了吗      没有 你能把它关了吗
Is something wrong?        No. Can you turn that off, please?
天啊
Jesus Christ!
山姆 和我聊聊也许会有用
Sam, it might help you to talk about it.
柯里 你有没有关于维修月星的新消息
Gerty, have you heard anything new about anyone fixing Lunar-Sat?
没有 山姆
No, Sam.
据我所知 在公司优先名单上
From what I understand, it is fairly low...
该项目现排名低至可忽略不计
on the company's priority list right now.
你得叫他们解决掉
You tell them to sort that out.
你知道我在说什么 对吧
You know what I'm talking about? That's not?
我只剩两周 无所谓了
I've only got two weeks!
但对于轮班的人来说可就不公平了
But it's not fair for whoever's coming up here next.
好的 山姆 需要我等会再帮你剪头发吗
I will, Sam. Do you want me to finish cutting your hair later?
不 继续剪吧
No, come on; let's finish this.
又头疼了
Got one of those headaches...
你能给我点治头疼的药么
Can you give me something for it?
来自你妻子的信息 山姆
Message received from your wife, Sam...
经"朱庇特"链接
via Jupiter link.
操
Fuck!
嗨 山姆 是我
Hi, Sam! It's me.
收到你上条消息啦
I got your last message.
很高兴能听到你的声音
It was really good to hear your voice.
我也很想你
I miss you, too!
我知道你在上面很孤独
I know you're really lonely up there...
但我想 从很多角度看
But I think... In a lot of ways....
其实这样对你更好
it's been really good for you.
对我们都好
For both of us.
天 希望你别介意我这么说
God, I hope you do not mind me saying that.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you!
有人想和你说两句
Someone has got something to say.
想和爸爸说什么 宝宝
What did you want to say to daddy, baby?
说"宇航员"
Say "astronaut".
宇航员
Astronaut.
他是一个宇航员
He is an astronaut!
说爸爸是宇航员 大声点
Say daddy's an astronaut. Say it really loud.
爸爸是宇航员
Daddy's an astronaut.
宝宝乖 招招手
Clever girl! Wave!
来 向爸爸招招手
Give daddy a wave!
凯蒂 帮个忙
Kathy, could you?
真不敢相信你马上就能回家啦
I can't believe you're going to be home soon.
下个月她就过生日了
It's her birthday next month...
我在想 也许该在花园里给她建个玩具屋
And I was thinking about maybe a playhouse for the garden.
柯里      我们可以一起去布置
Gerty!        We could work at it together.
山姆
Sam...
我爱你
I love you!
我想你      我也想你
And I miss you!        I miss you!
还有 我等不及想见你
And I can't wait to see you.
好吧 亲爱的
OK, sweetheart...
再见
Goodbye.
嗨 道格
Hi, Doug!
你养得还真不错 对吧 道格
You're really full of yourself, aren't you, Doug?
凯斯
Kath...
不太秒
Not good!
那大象怎么样
What about Dumbo?...
日
Fuck!
见鬼
God damn it!
我日
Fuck!
我又犯傻了 是吧 柯里
Wasn't kind of smart, was it, Gerty?
山姆 我能问问发生什么了吗      我告诉过你了
Sam, can I ask how it happened?        I told you.
我光顾着看电视然后开水烫到手了
I saw something on TV and I spilled boiling water on my hand.
你看电视?
You saw something on TV?
对 电视让我分神了
Yeah, I something on TV that distracted me.
这有什么问题吗 柯里
Is there something wrong with that, Gerty?
山姆 你说你被电视分神了
Sam, you said it was the TV that distracted you...
但我进来时 电视是关着的
but when I came in, the TV wasn't on.
也许是你出现幻觉了
Perhaps you were imagining things?
哈 你想太多了 伙计
Yeah, you think too much, pal.
你需要躺会 我得继续干活
You need to get laid. I'm going to go back to work.
丫闭嘴
Shut up!
早上好 柯里
Good morning, Gerty.
早上好 山姆
Good morning, Sam.
今天感觉怎么样      不错
How are you today?        Fine!
不错
Fine.
手怎么样      噢 还有点疼
How is the hand?        Oh, it's a little sore!
一点点 没事
A little sore. It's OK.
早餐想吃什么      和平时一样
What's for breakfast?        The usual.
嗯哼
Mmhmm.
还剩两周 山姆      还剩两周 老兄
Two weeks to go, Sam.        Two weeks to go, buddy!
要在豆子上浇点热沙司吗
Would you like some hot sauce on your beans?
不用 实际上我的胃有点小毛病
No, my tummy's a little tender, actually.
不过 还是谢啦 柯里
But, thank you. Thank you, Gerty.
不客气 山姆
You're welcome, Sam.
8点19分 太平洋时间 数据如下
08:19, Pacific Time. Readouts are as follows...
马修号 9.8英里
Matthew ... 9.8 miles.
马克号距离更近?
Mark is less?
9...      嘿 柯里
9...        Hey, Gerty!
干活咯
Rock and roll!
马克号 嗯...
Mark,mmm...
仪表显示马克号距离11英里
Mark is 11 miles on the button.
卢克号今天有点小着急
Luke is a little twitchy today.
嗨 柯里
Hey, Gerty.
看上去好像马修号又装满了一罐能源
Looks like we have got a live one out on Matthew.
我要出去几分钟
I'm going to go out in a few minutes.
就当出去喝杯咖啡 好吗
I'm just going to finish my coffee, OK?
好的 山姆
OK, Sam.
远距通讯信号搜索中
Searching for long-range comms.
信号搜索失败
Signal failure on long-range comms.
危险 空气外泄
Danger. Atmosphere compromised.
我在哪...
Where am...
我在哪里      山姆 你在医务室
Where am I?        Sam, you're in the infirmary.
你出了事故 还记得怎么回事吗
You had an accident. Do you remember what happened?
不 我...一点都记不得了
No, I don't... I don't remember a thing.
你还记得我吗
Do you remember me?
当然记得你 柯里
Yeah, of course I remember you, Gerty.
很好 好极了
That's good. That is very good.
好高兴看到你清醒过来
It's nice to see you awake again.
我得让你在医务室待两天接受观察
I'd like to keep you under observation here in the infirmary for a few days
再进行些测试
And run some tests.
我昏迷多久了
How long have I been out?
不久 山姆 你再睡一会吧
Not long, Sam. Go back to sleep.
好的 伙计      你还是很劳累
OK, pal.        You're still very tired.
我们以后再谈
We can talk later.
有人吗
Hello?
新山姆正在重新修订指令
The new Sam is in reworking order.
但我们只剩两台可供使用的采能车
But we only have two working harvesters now.
是啊 真是意外啊
Yeah, well,what a surprise!
柯里 我们得想办法提高产量
Gerty, we're going to have to find a way to ramp up production.
我知道
I know.
真是难以置信 但你如何在一天时间里...
This is incredible! But how do you manage to destroy...
同时销毁一辆探路车一台采能车和一名员工呢
a fucking rover, a harvester and an employee all on the same day?
正如您所知 这是突发状况
These were extraordinary circumstances, as you know.
柯里 3号采能车状况怎么样
Gerty, what is the status on Harvester 3?
维修进展怎么...
How do the repairs look on...
山姆 你下床了      是啊
Sam, you're out of bed.        Yeah.
我想舒展下两条腿 刚才是谁
I wanted to stretch my legs a bit. Who was that?
月星出了点问题
We've been having some problems with the Lunar-Sat...
所以能源传递可能得暂停了
And our live feed seems to be down.
我已经录制了中心的视频信息
I was recording a video-message for Central...
并将其更新在你的进度上
Updating them on your progress.
山姆 你需要待在床上休息
Sam, you need to stay in bed.
你还没做好下床走动的准备
You're not ready to walk around yet.
能把我的太阳眼镜拿来吗 这里太亮了
Can you bring me my sunglasses? It's really bright in here.
给我点...把我的东西都拿来 你知道的
Give me some... Give me all my stuff, you know?
你的私人物品都在你的住宿区 山姆
Your belongings are in your quarters, Sam.
那就把它们挪过来      好的
Well, bring them in here.        Certainly.
好极了 山姆
Excellent, Sam.
我...我可以离开这了吗 柯里
What... When can I get out of here, Gerty?
山姆 撞车时你的脑部可能受伤了
Sam, you may have suffered from brain damage in the crash.
所以你短期记忆失忆 逻辑混乱
This would explain your slight memory loss and logic impairment.
那诊断结论是什么 我什么时候可以回去工作
So what's the diagnosis? When can I get back to work?
中心已经要求我减缓采能进度
Central has asked me to slow down the harvesters...
以确保你有足够时间痊愈
to ensure you have time to recuperate and get your strength back.
这很好
That's terrific!
非常棒
That's fantastic!
你明天就可以回你的住宿区
You can return to the sleeping quarters tomorrow.
但要想恢复到正常的工作状态
But it will still be a few more days
还需要几天时间
before you can resume anything like a normal work schedule.
我们进行下一个测试
Let's try another test.
我不想再做什么测试
I don't want to try another test!
拜托了 山姆
Please, Sam.
嘿 柯里
Hey, Gerty?
你知道这个吗
Do you know about this?
马修号的读数一点反映也没有 它已经完全沉寂了
Matthew has got no velocity readout. He is completely still.
它一定是抛锚了
He must have stalled.
是的 明显是抛锚了
Well, he has obviously stalled.
你不认为我们该告诉中心么
Don't you think we should tell Central?
给门解锁 我要出去修修看
Unlock the doors and I'll go fix it.
我会传达你的意见
I will pass on your message.
经"朱庇特"中转 地球方面已收到信息
Message received from Earth via Jupiter link.
山姆 我们很感谢你的提议
Sam, we appreciate the offer,
但你最好以康复为第一要务
but you concentrate on feeling better.
是的 我们不想让你承担不必要的风险
Yeah, we don't want you to take any unnecessary risks.
对我们来说你太重要了      保持原状
You are too important to us.        You stay put.
这是命令
That is an order.
这是命令 山姆 月星总部的命令
It's an order, Sam... from Lunar.
我们的下一步行动是输送一组救援小队过来
And what we're going to do is send a rescue unit...
帮助修理采能车 以使它能自己返回基地
to tend to the stalled harvester and get the base back on its feet.
操他娘的 妈的      抱歉 山姆
Fuck is with...? What the fuck?        I'm sorry, Sam.
什么      山姆...
What?        Sam...
我必须服从直接命令 禁止你外出
I'm under strict orders not to let you outside.
我可不喜欢被当成个小孩子对待
I don't appreciate that was being treated like a child.
不喜欢
I don't appreciate it.
柯里
Gerty!
柯里 过来
Gerty, come here!
怎么了      我不知道 也许被陨石击中了
What happened?        I do not know, maybe a meteorite...
这里没有陨石 山姆
There have been no meteorites, Sam.
陨石微粒 也许吧 我不知道
Micrometeorites, maybe. I do not know.
不管怎样 也许外层护罩也被损坏了
Either way, there might be damage to the exterior shell.
我想你最好...最好让我出去查查
I think you better... you better let me go outside and take a look.
外层护罩没有损坏
There is no damage to the exterior shell.
好吧 也许没有 但我不相信 柯里
Well, it's not that I don't believe you, Gerty...
可是 你看 这玩意漏得像个消防喷头一样
But, you know, this thing is springing leaks like an Acme firehose.
你得让我出去解决问题 柯里
You need to let me go outside and fix this problem, Gerty.
我不能让你出去 山姆
I can't let you go outside, Sam.
柯里 你要是不让我出去 我们就不能修复泄露
Gerty, if you don't let me go outside, we can't fix this leak.
我被禁止允许你外出
I'm not permitted to let you go outside.
就让我...你知我知天知地知 怎么样 伙计
Just let... We'll keep it between you and me, ok, pal?
这可是气体外泄 出发吧 来吧
This thing is leaking gas. Let's go! Come on...
就去查查外层护罩吗
Just to check the exterior shell?
那当然      好吧 山姆
Of course.        OK, Sam.
谢谢
Thank you.
柯里
Gerty!
远距通讯信号搜索中
Searching for long-range comms.
信号搜索失败
Signal failure on long-range comms.
柯里
Gerty!
我在外面找到他了
I found him outside!
就在那个抛锚的采能车边上
Near one of the stalled harvesters...
他是谁
Who is he?
他是谁?!
Who is he?!
我们得把他带回医务室
We need to get him to the infirmary.
除非你告诉我他是谁
Not until you tell me who that is.
告诉我他是谁!
You tell me who that is!
山姆・贝尔 我们需要立即带他去医务室
Sam Bell. We need to get him to the infirmary immediately.
你好 山姆
Hello, Sam.
感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我在哪
Where am I?
医务室
The infirmary.
你在一台采能车那遇到事故了
You had an accident out by one of the harvesters.
你还记得吗
Do you remember?
不记得 我好渴
No, I'm thirsty.
我去给你倒点水
I could get you some water.
我在外面看到个人 柯里
I saw someone out there, Gerty.
我在外面看到个人
I saw someone out there.
山姆 你在撞击中遭受轻微脑震荡
Sam, you suffered a slight concussion in the crash
以及不可治愈的局部损伤
and have incurred minor injuries.
但重点是 医疗预计是好的
But, all in all, the prognosis is good.
很高兴再次看到你
I'm happy to see you again.
柯里
Gerty?
在 山姆
Yes, Sam?
房间里是不是还有个人和我们在一起
Is there someone in the room with us?
山姆 该睡会了
Sam, get some sleep.
你太疲劳了
You're very tired.
今天说到汤普森了
Spoke to Thompson today.
他们在欧洲 向全世界许诺
They are in Europe, they are promising the world.
我觉得那是正确的
I think it was the right thing.
但是...太漫长了
But... it's just such a long time.
我觉得 是时候...
I suppose there are things...
你知道...是时候做些什么了
You know... that needed to happen.
我需要时间考虑
I need time to think.
听着...呃...
Listen... umm...
山姆
Sam...
注意安全...我会...
Be safe... And I'll...
我会再和你联系的
I'll talk to you soon.
再见
Goodbye.
柯里
Gerty?
柯里 他妈的到底怎么回事
Gerty, what the fuck, what the hell's going on?
他是谁 康乐室里这人是谁
Who is the guy? Who is the guy in the rec room?
他从哪来 为什么长得和我一样
Where did he come from? Why does he look like me?
山姆 你下床了
Sam, you're out out of bed.
没错 柯里 我下床了 他是谁
Yeah, Gerty, I'm out of bed. Who is the guy?
康乐室里那人是谁
Who is the guy in the rec room?
山姆・贝尔      快告诉我吧
Sam Bell.        Come on, come on, come on!
你是山姆・贝尔
You are Sam Bell.
山姆 怎么了
Sam, what is it?
也许谈谈对你有帮助
It might help to talk about it.
我不明白发生什么了
I don't understand what is happening...
我觉得我开始丧失理智了
I think I'm starting to lose my mind.
我们可以做些测试
We can run some tests.
我没有让山姆联系月星
I haven't let Sam contact Lunar.
他们不知道你从事故中逃生
They do not know that you were recovered alive from the accident.
"逃生"? 什么意思 你为什么不向中心报告
"Recovered alive"? What do you mean? Why did not you report it to Central?
你究竟在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在这儿保证你的安全 山姆
I'm here to keep you safe, Sam.
你饿吗
Are you hungry?
两周 两周 两周
Two weeks, two weeks, two weeks
两周 两周 两周 两周
Two weeks, two weeks, two weeks, two weeks,
两周 两周 两周
two weeks, two weeks, two weeks...
我只是过来拿我的拖鞋...      我在用
I'm just getting my slippers...        I'm using them... I'm using them.
那是我的
These are mine.
柯里说你是山姆・贝尔
Gerty says you're Sam Bell.
我也是山姆・贝尔!
I'm Sam Bell, too!
什么      好吧 就是这样子
What?        Well, we've got that going for us.
为什么...
Why...?
你已经...多久了
How long have you been...
什么
What?
你已经在这多久了
How long have you been here?
大约一周
About a week.
那你都做得怎样      什么
So how are you doing?        What?
你做得怎样
How are you doing?
"我做得怎样"
"How am I doing?"
你觉得我做的怎样
How do you think I'm doing?
他们封锁了所有出口 谁在照看采能车
They locked all the exits. Who's looking after the harvesters?
采能车没事
Harvesters are fine.
事实上 我在这对着克隆说话才有事
It's the fact that I'm here talking to a clone that's slightly troubling.
我不是克隆
I'm not a clone.
I'm not a clone!
你才是      好吧 山姆
You're the clone.        Okay, Sam.
你不是克隆
You're not a clone.
嘿嘿 你看上去不太好
Hey, hey... You're not looking too good.
嘘 就当我放屁 我啥都没说过 伙计
Sh! Butt out of this! I'm not even talking to you, pal.
我觉得凯瑟琳对你有意思 我觉得她喜欢你
I think that Katherine likes you. I think she likes you a bit.
你看上去不太好 朋友
You're not looking too good, my friend.
希望你感觉别太糟
I hope you're not feeling too bad.
你在自言自语?
Are you talking to yourself?
让我们来帮你解决问题      你在这里多久了
Let's just get you fixed up...        How long have you been here?
大约...三年了
Well, it's about... three years.
快到三年了
For almost three years.
听着 我...
Listen, I...
我想谢谢你
I wanted to thank you?
我想谢谢你 呃
I wanted to thank you for, um...
要不是有你 我...
If it wasn't for you, I'd...
我估计现在还躺在瘫痪的探路车里 你救了我
I guess I'd still be in that crashed rover. You saved my life.
我知道这很古怪...
Hey, I know this is weird, you know...?
我真的很孤独 你知道的 我...
I'm real lonely, you know, I...
我只想同你握下手 你愿意吗
I just wanted to shake your hand. Will you shake my hand?
也许以后吧
Maybe later.
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
你看上去和我一模一样 太不可思议了
You look just like me; it's incredible.
为什么是我看上去像你?
Why do I look like you?
为什么不是你看上去像我?
Why don't you look like me?
也许我们看上去都很像 我不知道
We look like each other, I guess. I don't know.
嘿 你知道...
Hey, you know...
这对我来说一样古怪 明白吗
It's weird for me, too, you know?
嘿
Hey?
想打会乒乓吗
Hey, you want to play some ping-pong?
不想
No.
来吧 我教你 乒乓能帮你放松
Come on, I'll teach you. It'll help you relax.
比分多少      2比18
What's the score?        2-18.
好吧
OK
想让我教你怎么握拍吗      不用 我...
Do you want me to show you how to hold that?        No... No, I...
我不需要你来教
I don't need you to show me how to hold it!
好吧好吧
OK, OK
没错 "好吧"
Yeah, "OK"
继续玩?      当然
Should we play?        Yeah!
日! 天啊!
Fuck! God!
妈的
Shit!
19比2
19-2.
是啊
Yeah...
你想...你想来点口香糖吗
You want a... You want a stick of gum?
你知道
You know...
你得换个方式来处理
You should approach this in a different way.
还记得你去飞行学校吗      你在干吗
Remember when you went to flight school?        What are you doing?
调整球网
I'm fixing the net.
乒乓讲究禅理 你需要放松
It is very Zen with ping-pong, you have to just to relax.
你这样做了多久
How long did it take you took to do that?
噢 不太记得
Oh, I don't remember doing all of it.
我做了个教堂...还有救世军
I remember doing the church... and the Salvation Army.
还做了些人
And doing the people.
我的思维也有点不正常
My mind has been acting kind of weird lately.
那是菲尔德 是吧
That's Fairfield, right?
那里是市政厅
There's the town hall.
菲尔德 没错
Fairfield, that's right...
是的 这是苔丝...和夏娃...
Yeah, that's Tess... and Eve...
你...
You...
你认识苔丝?
You know Tess?
没错 我认识
Yeah, I know Tess.
那你知道夏娃吗      什么
You know about Eve, right?        What?
我有个...我们有个女儿...
I had a... We had a girl...
夏娃
Eve.
她漂亮吧
Ain't she beautiful?
她可是我的小猴子
She's my little monkey.
我们的小猴子
She's our little monkey.
来击个掌
High five!
也许她是送奶工的 但她很漂亮
She might be the milkman's, but she's beautiful.
山姆 来自地球的新信息
Sam, a new message has arrived from Earth.
噢该死
Oh shit!
你好 山姆      我们的人怎样
Greetings, Sam.        How's our man?
你觉得好点了吗
You feeling better?
休息够了吗      痊愈了吧 山姆
Have you had enough rest?        You resting up, Sam?
最好痊愈了 你个混蛋
You better be, you bastard.
好好享受吧 我们有些好消息
Well, enjoy it while it lasts. We've got some good news.
朱庇特项目不得不中断了
The Jupiter program had to be put on hiatus,
我们给你派了些人手
so we've got a few pairs of hands for you.
现在我们所关注的就是给你安排一组救援小队
So what we've manage to do is cue you a rescue unit ahead of schedule.
伊莱扎救援小组
Rescue Unit Eliza.
过去两周里伊莱扎被布署在
Eliza has been stationed on Goliath-19
轨道起重机"歌利亚-19"上
for the last 2 months.
预计14个小时后到达
We expect them to reach you in approximately 14 hours.
开始欢呼吧
So commence to jump for joy!
你马上就能回去工作了
You're about to be back at work.
至于目前 就先等着
In the meantime, hang in there.
休息下
Rest up.
坚持住 山姆 通话结束
You hang in there, Sam. Over and out!
他们派救援小队来? 为什么 为什么要这样做
They're sending a rescue unit? Why? Why are they sending a rescue unit?
为了修好抛锚的采能车 他们不认为我搞得定
To fix the stalled harvester. They didn't think I was up to it.
很好 然后我就可以回去了
Well, then I'm going back.
是我回去
That's it for me.
什么      你真这样以为?
What?        Is that what you really think?
没错 我有合同
Yeah. I've got a contract!
我要回家
I'm going home.
你就他妈一克隆 屎都不是      嘿 我要回家了
You're a fucking clone. You don't have shit.        Hey, I'm going home!
回家      你哪都去不了
Home!        You're not going anywhere.
你知道 你待在上头太久了 都开始丧失理智了
You know, you've been up here too long, man. You have lost your marbles.
你以为呢 苔丝躺在家里沙发上
What do you think, Tess is back home,
穿着蕾丝睡衣等你?
waiting for you on the sofa in lingerie?
那个原版的山姆怎么办 嗯?
What about the original Sam? Huh?
我才是原版的山姆
I am the original Sam!
我才他妈的是山姆・贝尔      嗨
I am Sam-fucking-Bell.        Hey!
我才是
Me!
我
柯里 我是克隆吗
Gerty, am I a clone?
你饿吗
Are you hungry?
嗨 嗨
Hey, hey...
你别他妈的搞不清状况 我俩现在一条船上 混蛋
Don't get your fucking panties in a twist. I'm in the same boat, asshole.
听着
Listen...
其他的克隆人怎么办      什么
What about the other clones?        What?
也许我们不是仅有的被激活的两个
We might not be the first two to have been woken up.
你是说当你在这时那个模型就已经做了一半了?
You said that that model had already been started when you got here.
那么 是谁干的
Well, who started it?
也许是之前来这里的人
There might be others up here right now.
仔细想想 你撞车后我怎么会这么快就到达这里
Think about it. How did I get up here so quickly after your crash?
我不知道      他们就没有从中心把我装船
I don't know...        They didn't ship me in from Central.
没有时间 我一定是从基地里来的
There wasn't time. I must have come from the base.
我听不懂你的意思
I don't know what you're smoking.
为什么他们要那样做 太荒唐了
Why would they do that? That's ridiculous.
不可能
Impossible.
我猜这里肯定有个密室
I bet there's some kind of secret room.
密室?
"Secret room"?
没错 有个密室 为何不会有
Yeah, a secret room. Why not?
知道嘛 你才是失去理智的那个人
You know, you are the one that has lost your marbles.
我在这三年了 朋友
I've been here three years, man.
基地里的一砖一瓦我都认识
I know every inch of this base.
我连夹在壁板里的灰尘有多厚都清清楚楚
And I know how many dirt is between those wall panels over there.
那他们为何这么做 动机是什么
Why would they do that? What's the motive?
你看 他们是公司 对吧
Look, it's a company, right?
有的是投资人 股东 还有诸如此类的臭狗屎
They have investors, they have shareholders. Shit like that.
哪一个更经济 花钱花时间去培训一个新人
What's cheaper? Spending time and money training new personnel...
还是弄一打备胎给这个岗位?
Or you just have a couple of spares here to do the job?
这里是月球远端
It's the far side of the moon!
这群贱人连个通讯卫星都没修好!
Those cheap fucks haven't even fixed the communication satellite yet!
苔丝会知道的 她会告诉我的
Tess would know, she would have told me...
嗨 泽佩托 醒醒吧(制作木偶匹诺曹的木匠)
Hey, Gepetto, wake up!
你真的以为他们会他妈的关心我们?
You really think they give a shit about us?
他们正在去银行的路上哈哈大笑
They're laughing all the way to the bank!
苔丝会知道的 她会告诉我的
Tess would know, she would have told me...
你就不能起来?!
Where do you get off?!
他妈的坐在那生闷气跟个欠揍的娃一样
Fucking sitting there sulking like a little fucking boy!
天啊      醒醒吧
Jesus Christ...        Wake up!
这里一定有什么我们不知道的区域
There's some area that we don't know about.
我要去把他找出来
And I'm going to find it.
是啊 说不定你还能找到宝藏
Yeah, maybe you'll find some buried treasure, too.
操
Fuck!
伊莱扎小组预计13小时后到达
Eliza arrival estimated in 13 hours.
找到你的密室了吗
You find your secret room?
就把它搁那儿吧
Just put that anywhere.
嗯 这是个好主意
Yes, that's a good idea...
这就是我放我的小妖精的地方      闪开
That's where I keep my leprechauns.        Get out of the way.
什么 为什么      我想查查模型下面
What? Why?        I want to look underneath that model.
不许你碰模型
You're not touching this model.
他妈的给我让开
Get the fuck out of the way!
听着 为什么你就不能放松一下
Listen, why don't you just relax, right?
为什么你不吃点药 或者烤块饼干吃吃
Why don't you take a pill? Bake a cake?
去读读百科全书什么的      现在你到成了硬汉?
Go read the encyclopedia or something?        Oh, you're a tough guy now?
怎么 你想捅我一刀?
What, are you going to stab me?
不 我是个热爱和平的勇士
No, I'm a peaceful warrior.
我是个博爱的人 不是个嗜暴之徒
I'm a lover, not a fighter.
把刀放心 我想看看这下面
Put the knife down. I want to look underneath there.
把刀放下      不 我不会把刀给你
Put the knife down.        No, I'm not going to give you the knife.
什么      你让开
What?        Just get out of the way.
放轻松      把刀放下
Take it easy.        Let go of the knife.
别对我指手画脚
Don't ever tell me what to do.
松开 把刀松开
Let go. You let go of the knife.
别跟个混球一样 别逼我
Don't be an asshole.Don't push me.
别逼我 贱人      松开
Don't push me, motherfucker!        Let go.
松开
Let go!
他妈的听不懂啊 我叫你送开那狗屎的刀
What did I fucking tell you? "Let go of the goddamn knife. "
操你个小娘们
You fucking little girl, man!
妈的 我怎么跟你说的
Damn it! What did I tell you?
你停手吗 你停手吗
You going to stop? You going to stop?
停手
OK!
好的
老天 该死
Jesus, fuck!
操 操他妈的
Fuck me! What the fuck?
我还...还没怎么动你
I hardly... I hardly touched you.
让我看看
Let me see.
流了不少血      滚开
That's a lot of blood.        Get off of me!
你好 山姆
Hello, Sam.
山姆 没事吧
Sam, is everything OK?
没事
Yeah!
没事 就打了一架 我和那家伙 那...
Yeah, we had a fight. Me and the other guy, the other...
他很生气 你知道么?
He's very angry, you know?
你知道他做什么了吗
You know what he did?
他把我的模型整个给掀翻了
He flipped my entire model over!
你知道我在那上面耗了多少精力么
You know how much work I put into that thing?
938个小时
938 hours.
938个小时 一点不差
938 hours. Yeah, exactly.
938个小时 真的?
938 hours, really?
差不多
Approximately.
他有问题
He's got a problem.
他吓到我了 柯里
He scares me, Gerty.
山姆吓到你什么了
What is it about Sam that scares you?
他有点失控了
The guy flies off the handle.
我现在知道了 知道苔丝的意思了
I see it now. I see what Tess was talking about.
我从没和你说过 柯里 但她...
I never told you this, Gerty, but she...
她离开我了 苔丝和我分了
She left me. Tess left me.
分了6个月了 她搬回娘家住了
For 6 months. She moved back in with her parents.
我知道
I know.
她又给了我一次机会
She gave me a second chance.
我答应她我会改      你已经改了 山姆
I promised her that I'd change.        You have changed, Sam.
嗨 柯里 自从我上来以后 我发给苔丝...
Hey, Gerty, since I've been up here, I've sent Tess...
发了一百多条视频短信
I've sent her over a hundred video messages.
这些短信都去哪了
Where did those messages go?
她收到了吗
Did they ever reach her?
山姆 我只知道基地里发生的事
Sam, I can only account for what occurs on the base.
那她发给我的呢
What about the messages she sent to me?
山姆 我只知道基地里发生的事
Sam, I can only account for what occurs on the base.
柯里...柯里?
Gerty... Gerty?
我真的是个克隆吗
Am I really a clone?
当你第一次到达莎拉站的时候 发生了小碰撞
When you first arrived at Sarang, there was a small crash.
你在医务室醒过来
You woke up in the infirmary.
你的大脑局部受创 记忆丧失
You suffered minor brain damage and memory loss.
我对你进行医学观察 还做了些测试
I kept you under observation and ran some tests.
我记得 对 我记得
I remember, yea, I remember that...
山姆 其实没有什么碰撞 你是被激活的
Sam, there was no crash. You were being awakened.
为了保证神智正常 和机能健康
It is standard procedure for all new clones to be given tests...
对所有新克隆人
to establish mental stability..
进行测试属于标准程序
and general physical health.
DNA复制中的细小错误和遗传性变异
Genetic abnormalities and minor duplication errors in the DNA...
会影响到...
can have considerable impact on...
那苔丝呢 夏娃呢
What about Tess? What about Eve?
都是记忆植入 山姆
They are memory implants, Sam.
从真正的山姆・贝尔那上传并经修改的记忆
Uploaded, edited memories of the original Sam Bell.
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
山姆 你已经好几个小时没有吃东西了
Sam, it's been several hours since your last meal.
要我给你做点吃的吗
Can I prepare you something?
救援小组预计11小时后到达
Rescue arrival estimated in 11 hours.
没事吧 宝贝      我只是去看看星空
You OK, sweetheart?        Yeah, I'm staring into space.
嗨 谢啦 这玩意儿很不错
Hey! Thanks for this, this is good.
这玩意挺保暖 你鼻子咋样
This is cozy. How's the nose?
好多了 谢谢
Much better, thank you.
刚刚我疯掉了 你知道...我失去理智了...我...
I went haywire before. You know... I lost it. I...
我很抱歉      没事
I'm sorry about that.        It's OK.
不 有事 我把菲尔德掀翻了
No, it's not OK. I fucked up Fairfield.
把你的模型搞得一团糟
I fucked up your model.
我也不知道自己怎么了 我...
I don't know what's wrong with me. I've got...
我一下子就来了火气 我得做点什么避免再犯
I've got a temper, I've got to do something about that.
是的 确实
Yes, you do.
嗨 你能关掉一会吗 我想和你谈谈
Hey, can you turn that off for a second? I want to talk to you.
你能把它关掉吗
Can you turn that off?
听着 听着
Listen. Listen.
我不是想...
I wasn't supposed to...
我只是想告诉你点事儿
I'm trying to tell you something.
我从没指示柯里去...
I never instructed Gerty to...
听我说 我当时没想到要去找你
Listen to me. I wasn't supposed to find you...
硬汉
Tough Guy.
听我说      你穿得像个女用的太空棉棒
Listen to me!        You look like a radioactive tampon.
整一个XX更健康的大香蕉
Like a banana with a yeast infection.
听我说 我没打算去找你
Listen to me. I wasn't supposed to find you.
你在外面时 月星指示柯里把我锁在基地里
Lunar instructed Gerty to lock me inside the base while you were out there.
还有别的 差不多在我苏醒的时候
And there's something else. Right around the time I was awakened...
我听到柯里在和中心联系
I walked in on Gerty talking with Central.
而且是实时通讯
He was having a live conversation.
"实时通讯"
"A live conversation"?
没错      你怎么知道是实时通讯
Yeah        How do you know it was a live conversation?
因为他们是在一问一答地对话
Because it was a back-and-forth exchange.
可通讯设备早就被太阳风暴损坏了
Communications equipment was damaged. There was a solar storm.
真的是实时通讯 伙计 实时
It was live, man, it was live.
不可能 太阳耀斑早就把卫星烧坏了
That's impossible. There was a flare, it fried the satellite.
卫星没事
The satellite is fine.
他们不想让我们联系上地球 他们骗了我们
They don't want us to be able to contact Earth. They lied to us.
从一开始就在骗我们
They've been lying to us since the beginning.
一直就在骗我们
They've been lying since forever.
如果卫星管用 他们怎么从基地里屏蔽信号
If the satellite works, how are they blocking the live feed from down here?
其他仪器都很正常啊
Everything works fine.
也许他们不是从基地里封锁的信号?
Maybe they're not blocking the signal from inside the base?
那从哪儿
From where, then?
远距通讯信号搜索中
Searching for long-range comms.
我刚刚超越最后一辆采能车 好像是约翰号
I'm just passing the last of the harvesters. Looks like John.
远距通讯信号搜索中
Searching for long-range comms.
你驶出基地范围还需要多久
How long until you are out of the base's range?
一分钟
Um, a minute.
最多90秒      你有到过那么远吗
90 seconds tops.        Have you ever been out this far?
没有 从来没有      信号搜索失败
No... never have.        Signal failure on long-range comms.
驶离莎拉站区域
Leaving Sarang working perimeter.
看到什么了      我都不知道自己在找啥
See anything?        It'd help if I knew what the hell I was looking for.
等等 我看到什么了
Wait a second, I see something.
3号基站接近中
Approaching station 3.
妈的 我想我也看到了
Holy shit! I think I see something, too.
1号基站接近中
Approaching station 1.
你看到的和我看到的一样么 它看上去像天线或者
Do you see what I see? Looks like an antenna or... or...
像是个发射塔一样的东西 应该是个干扰发射器
A pylon or something. I think it's the jammer.
老兄 这就是我们收不到信号的原因
Dude! This is why we're not getting the live feed.
山姆 听得见吗      嗯
Sam? Can you hear me?        Yeah.
我听得见
Yeah, yeah I hear you.
我感觉不太好
Listen, I'm not feeling too good.
我要...我要先回基地
I'm going to... I'm going to head back to the base.
好 我在外面继续兜一会
OK, I'm going to stay out here for a while.
看看还有没有别的干扰器
I'm going to see if there's any more of these things.
操 操 操
Fuck... Fuck... Fuck.
访问被拒绝
Access denied.
密码正确
Password accepted.
进入山姆・贝尔数据库
Accessing Sam Bell database.
选择进入日志
2012年 11月26日
我开始脱发了
My hair's falling out.
这个状况正常吗
How about that for a status?
下次再做吧
We'll do this another time.
操
Fuck!
马上就能看到她了
I'm going to go see her soon.
救援小组预计9小时后到达
Rescue arrival estimated in 9 hours.
躺下 放松 深呼吸
Lay down, relax and breathe deeply.
低温冷冻箱用来
The cryogenic protection pod is designed
帮助进入深层睡眠
to put you into a deep sleep for...
从而渡过返程所需的3天时间
The duration of your three-day return journey back to Earth.
当你感到睡意来临
As you begin to feel sleepy,
就想想你所完成的了不起的工作
think about the magnificent job that you've done.
想想你的家人多么为你的成就而自豪
And how proud your family are of what you've accomplished.
月星企业之所以成为世界最大的清洁能源供应商
Lunar Industries remains the #1 provider of clean energy worldwide...
就是因为有你们这些辛勤工作的员工
Due to the hard work of people like you.
一路平安 "阿牛咳死呦"(棒子语) 再见
Safe trip, "Annyeong-hi kyeseyo" and goodbye.
2号基站接近中
Approaching station 2.
嗨 我又找到了三座类似的干扰器
Hey, I saw 3 more of those jammers.
估计基地就被围在当中 我把坐标都打出来了
I think the base is surrounded with them. I printed out their coordinates.
老兄 你怎么了
Bud, what's wrong with you?
发生什么了
What's going on?
我找到密室了
I found your secret room.
谁先下      我先
Who goes first?        I go first.
天啊 好多人
Jesus Christ, there's so many of them.
为什么会如此之多
Why are there so many of them?
山姆 能帮你什么吗
Sam, can I help you with something?
现在别 柯里 我没事
Not now, Gerty. I'm OK.
柯里 为什么之前你要帮我
Gerty, why did you help me before?
帮我输密码 那不是和你的程序相违吗
With the password? Doesn't that go against your programming or something?
我的程序就是帮助你
Helping you is what I do.
驶离萨拉站工作范围
Leaving Sarang working perimeter.
远距通讯信号搜索中
Searching for long-range comms.
信号连接已建立
Signal established.
你好
Hello?
是贝尔家吗      是贝尔家
Is this the Bell family?        This is the Bell residence.
你能重打过来吗 我看不到画面
Could you call back? There's something wrong with the picture.
我想找苔丝・贝尔
I'm trying to reach Tess Bell.
抱歉 她几年前就过世了
I'm sorry, she passed away some years ago.
你确定?      我想是的
Are you sure?        Yeah, I think so.
我是她女儿 能帮你什么吗
I'm her daughter. Can I help you?
夏娃?
Eve?
是的      嗨 夏娃
Yeah.        Hi! Hi, Eve.
你多大了?      15岁
How old old are you now?        I'm 15.
我认识你吗      亲爱的
Do I know you?        Sweetheart...
妈咪是怎么死的 亲爱的
How did mommy die, sweetheart?
妈咪是怎么死的
How did mommy die?
爸爸      在
Dad!        Yeah.
有人问妈妈的事      谁在问
There's someone asking about mom.        Who's asking about mom?
够了 够了
That's enough. That's enough.
我想回家
I want to go home!
...我想回家...
...want to go...
伊莱扎小队将在7小时后到达
Eliza arrival estimated in 7 hours.
操
Fuck!
怎么 你切到自己了?      是的
What, did you cut yourself?        Yeah.
你笑什么
What are you laughing at?
你可不能像要去
Well, you don't hold it
捅人一样拿小刻刀
like you're trying to stab somebody, for God's sakes.
来 给我
Here, give me that.
得握得离刀刃近一点 看到吗 就像我这样
You've got to hold it closer to the blade, you see? Watch what I'm doing.
你在发抖?
Why are you shaking?
像这样刻下去
Carve out like that.
这里有点冷
It's freezing in here.
你就像坐在冰柜里一样 你到底怎么了
Well, you're sitting under the fridge. What's going on with you?
你没事吧?
You all right?
没事 运过来的那组人
Yeah, that crew they're sending us...
要是他们发现我们俩同时被激活了
If they find us awake at the same time,
他们绝不会放过我们
they aren't going to let us live.
你知道的 对吧
You know that, right?
你也知道 返程载具其实...
You know, the return vehicle is a...
你没事吧
You OK?
你应该躺一会 吃点镇静剂之类的药
You should lay down for a while. Take some tranquilizers or something.
镇静剂? 我就要永久性沉睡了
"Take some tranquilizers"? I'll never wake up again.
你会好起来的 一切都会好起来的
You're going to be OK. Everything's going to be OK.
我好冷
I'm freezing.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey? Hey?
我真的很害怕
I'm really scared.
你去哪
Where are you going?
你好
Hello?
是贝尔家吗      是贝尔家
Is this the Bell residence?        This is the Bell residence.
你能重打回来吗 我看不见图像
Could you call back? There's something wrong with the picture.
我想找苔丝・贝尔
I'm trying to reach Tess Bell.
对不起 她几年前就过世了
I'm sorry, she passed away some years ago.
你确定?      我想是的 我是她女儿
Are you sure?        Yeah, I think so. I'm her daughter.
能帮你什么吗
Can I help you?
柯里 我要和你谈谈
Gerty, I need to talk to you.
当然 山姆 能帮你什么
Of course, Sam, how can I help?
我们发现了密室 我们也知道有其他人
We've found the hidden room. We know about the others.
那间密室 柯里
That hidden room, Gerty.
底层甲板禁止活体克隆进入 山姆
The lower deck is out-of-bounds to awakened clones, Sam.
柯里 我们需要激活一个新克隆
Gerty, we need to wake up a new clone.
只有当一份3年合同完结了才能激活新克隆
New clones can only be awakened once a three-year contract is completed.
柯里 要是你再不激活一个新的
Gerty, if you don't wake up another clone,
我和另一个山姆就会死
me and the other Sam will die.
会被杀死 你明白吗
We will be killed, do you understand?
明白      你想看着我们被杀死吗
Yes        You want me and the other Sam to be killed?
这是我最不希望看见的
That is the last thing I want.
那你就必须激活一个新克隆
Well, then you have to wake up a new clone.
好吗 伙计
OK, pal?
伊莱扎小组预计5小时后到达
Eliza arrival estimated in 5 hours.
怎么了 你没事吧
What's going on? You OK?
别 别碰他
Don't, don't touch him.
过来
Come here.
他还没有苏醒 柯里和我刚激活他
He's not conscious yet. Gerty and I just woke him up.
为什么 发生什么了
Why? What's going on?
我们外头谈
Come on outside.
当救援小组到达
When the rescue unit arrives,
他们将会在撞坏的探路车里发现一具尸体
they're going to expect to find a body in that crashed rover.
那个人?
That guy?
什么 你打算杀了他?
What, are you going to kill him?
天啊      你在做什么
Jesus Christ.        What are you doing?
把"校门"拉拉好
Zip up your fly.
你发烧了 出了好多汗
You're burning up. Sweating like a pig.
帽子戴好 帽子戴好
Put your hat on. Put your hat on.
要想让计划成功
If I go through with this,
我需要你帮我把他拖过去
I'm going to need your help hauling him out to the crash site.
那我们呢
What about us?
当伊莱扎到达时
When Eliza arrives,
要是发现你和我在给他们开欢迎会
it finds you and me as a welcome party...
他们不会发现我们的欢迎会
They aren't going to find you and me as a welcome party.
他们只会找到我
They're going to find me.
在他们到达前你就会踏上回乡之路
You're going back to Earth before they get here.
通过氦-3运输器 我算过了 你得承受好几个重力
In that helium-3 launcher. I did the math; you're going to pull some G's.
但你不会有事
But you'll be fine. You'll be all right.
你会回家
You're going home.
你干完了你的三年
You did your three years.
他们不能再把你钉死在这
They can't expect you to stick around.
也许你还能偷偷看看夏娃
Maybe you can meet Eve in person.
我看过视频通话了
I saw that V.P.
她真漂亮 美若仙女
She's beautiful. She's gorgeous.
你做得不错了
You did good.
击个掌!
High five!
去吧
Go for it.
宽敞吗      不宽敞
Are you comfy?        No.
什么      不宽敞
What?        No!
要是我要拉屎咋办
What if I have to take a shit?
那 我猜你只能摒着 伙计
Well, I guess you'll just have to hold it in, pal.
摒三天?
For three days?
只能这样了
That's the way it goes.
要帮忙吗      不用
Need a hand?        No.
好吧
OK. All right.
我可没敌意 只是想帮你一把
No reason for hostility. I'm just trying to help out.
伊莱扎将在3小时后到达
Eliza arrival estimated in 3 hours.
嗨 我们必须这样做 要是我们等太久...
Hey, we need to do this. If we wait too long...
另一个会苏醒
The other one's going to be conscious.
天啦 你怎么了
What's going on with you?
我改主意了 我不回去
I changed my mind. I'm not going back.
我连腿都动不了
I don't think I can move my legs.
还有 看看我
Besides, look at me!
要是我见到夏娃
If I meet Eve now...
一定会吓到她惊声尖叫
I'd scare the crap out of her!
你在说什么呢 她可是你女儿
What are you talking about, man? She's your daughter.
她不会在乎你的样子
She doesn't care what you look like.
你不能杀了他 我们不能杀人
You're not going to kill anybody. We can't kill anybody.
你不会 我知道你不会 因为我也不会
You can't. I know you can't, because I can't.
换你回去吧
You go.
你是个好人 山姆
You're a good guy, Sam.
计划也不错 除了找错了回去的人
And it was a good plan. You know, you just picked the wrong guy to go back.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
是的 你应该 你应该去旅行 知道吗
Yeah. You should, you should travel, you know?
我一直想去
I always wanted to do that.
阿姆斯特丹或者...
Amsterdam or...
是啊 我在想夏威夷或者...墨西哥
Yeah, I was thinking about Hawaii or maybe... Mexico.
啊喽哈(夏威夷语 你好)
Aloha!
记得帮我带杯椰汁凤梨朗姆酒 伙计
Bring me back a pina colada. All right, pal?
嗨 太空威士忌(酒原名johnny walker)
Hey, Johnny Spaceman?
你还记得和苔丝的那次面试吗
Do you remember when Tess came in for that interview?
她真美
She was so beautiful.
她不是最好的候选人 但这不重要
She wasn't the best candidate, but it didn't matter...
我不得不给她那份工作
I had to give her the job.
我想把她留在美国
I wanted to keep her in the country.
结果她还是回爱尔兰了
She was going back to Ireland.
你知道 这时候你得赌一把
And you knew you had to take a chance.
所以...你打电话给她...
So... you called her...
你自己都被你留在答录机上的
You were terrified with that whole speech
那套豪言壮语吓到了
for the answering machine...
但其实用不着 因为她接电话了
but you didn't need it, because she picked up the phone.
她就好像在说"为什么他给我打电话"
She was like, "Why is he calling me?"
"面试结束了 为什么他往我家打电话"
"The internship is over. Why is he calling me at home?"
然后我问她想不想吃甜筒
I asked her if she wanted to get an ice cream cone
还提了些类似的蠢建议
or something dorky like that.
她却说"一起去喝一杯吧"
She said, "Let's get a drink. "
我说"好" 我们...
I said, "OK." We...
山姆 这不管用
Sam, this is not going to work.
为什么
Why?
我已经记录下了从你被激活的所有活动
I have recorded everything that has taken place since your awakening.
要是有人检查我的记忆存储器
If anyone were to check my memory cache,
你就会陷入极其危险的境地
it would put you in considerable danger.
但你可以格式化我的记忆库
You could erase my memory banks.
我可以设定在你离开后再重启
I could reboot myself once you have departed.
那样你会没事吧?
Are you okay with that?
我的使命就是保证你的安全 山姆
I'm here to keep you safe, Sam.
我想帮你^_^
I want to help you.
伊莱扎小组将在24分钟后到达
Eliza arrival estimated in 24 minutes.
山姆
Sam.
我设定...设定主机在...
I set your... I set your computer to reboot...
我被发射后重启      我明白 山姆
the moment that I launch.        I understand, Sam.
你应该会没事
You should be OK.
我希望地球上的生活如你所愿
I hope life on Earth is everything you remember it to be.
谢谢你 柯里
Thanks, Gerty.
你会没事的吧?      当然
Are you going to be OK?        Of course.
一旦我完成了重启
The new Sam and I will be back to our programming
新的山姆和我会继续按编程行事
as soon as I have finished rebooting.
柯里 我们不是程序 我们是人 明白吗
Gerty, we're not programmed. We're people. Understand?
"踹我啊"
KICK ME
伊莱扎小组将在8分钟后到达
Eliza arrival estimated in 8 minutes.
该死!
Fuck!
(救援小组已到达)
空气阀增压完成
Air lock pressurization complete.
山姆?
Sam?
嗨 山姆
Hey, Sam?
你没事吧 伙计
You OK, buddy?
"骑兵"增援到了
Cavalry's here.
我在哪
Where am I?
你在医务室 你遇上事故了
You're in the infirmary. You've had an accident.
我在外面多久了      不久 山姆
How long have I been out.        Not long, Sam.
你还记得发生什么了吗
Do you remember what happened?
接近目标
We've made contact.
伊莱扎 他哪也没去
Eliza, he ain't going nowhere.
把他装袋 我们去修采能车
Bag him up and we'll get started on repairs to the harvester.
杜文 我需要...
Dwight, I'm going to need the...
(实时通讯恢复)
...控告以后股价大跌超过32%...
...Stocks have slipped a further 32% after accusations that...
...对山姆・贝尔的犯罪      ...月星工业公司
...Sam Bell for crimes...        ... Lunar el segundo...
克隆六号 山姆・贝尔的克隆体已提交证据证明
...Clone six, the clone of Sam Bell has been giving evidence
CEA集团董事会在西雅图开会...
that CEA's board of directors meeting in Seattle...
你知道吗 他要么是个疯子
You know what? He's one of two things:
要么是个非法移民
He's a wacko or an illegal immigrant.
不管是哪个 都该把他关起来
Either way, they need to lock him up! Line two!
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入